Guide to the Archives of Irish America Vertical Files AIA.013
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- E
  - Economy of Ireland, 2000 (Box 6)
  - Edmond of the Hill, Noble Hero and Wonderful Song (John O'Carney), 2012 (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - The E.E.C. Fraud, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Egan, Edward Michael J.C.D., 2000 (Box 29, File 22)
  - Eire Ireland - various articles - John F. Kennedy, 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Éire Philatelic Association, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Eire Society of Boston, 1960-1974 (Box 6)
  - Ellis Island, undated (Box 6)
  - Ellis Island: Dedication of Annie Moore Statue, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Emerald Association of Long Island, Inc., 1969-1978 (Box 6)
  - Emerald Association of Long Island, Inc., 2019 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Emerald Isle Festival, 1992-1993 (Box 6)
  - Emerald Isle Immigration Center, 1989-2015 (Box 6, Box 7, Box 20, Box 34, Folder 21-22, Box 30, Folder 1-2)
  - Emerald Isle Immigration Center, 25th Annual Dinner Dance, 2013 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Emerald Isle Immigration Center, Cultural Programs List, 2013 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Emerald Isle Immigration Center, Education: In Pursuit of the American Dream, 1993 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Emerald Isle Immigration Society, 1999, 2009-2011 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Emerald Platinum Plus, circa 1998-1999 (Box 7)
  - Emerald Society Board of Education City of New York Annual Dinner Dance, 1988 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - The Emmet Club, undated (Box 7)
  - Emigrant Information Pack, 2012 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Emigrant Savings Bank, 2000-2003 (Box 43, Folder 12, Box 45, Vhs 013.0005-013.0010, Betacam sp 013.0011-013.0016, Box 46, Betacam sp 013.0018-013.0028, Box 47, Vhs 013.0029-013.0040, Box 48, Vhs 013.0041-013.0052, Box 49, Vhs 013.0053-013.0059, Betacam sp 013.0060-013.0064, Box 50, Audiocassette 013.0068, Minidv 013.0069-013.0090, 013.0092-013.0094, Dat 013.0091, Box 51, Vhs 013.0065-013.0067, Dvcam 013.0095-013.0103, Box Shared Tamiment 170, 8mm film reel 013_0104, Box Shared Tamiment 088, Quarter inch audio reel 013.0105)
  - Emigrant Bank Savings - 150th Anniversary Book/Address Book, 2000 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Emmet, Thomas Addis Esq., undated (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - England Get Out of Ireland! No British Police in America!, undated (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Event Ads and Press Releases in Ireland, 1994-2009 (Box 7)
  - Event Ads and Press Releases in NYC [2 folders], 1988-2009 (Box 7)
  - Event Ads and Press Releases in U.S./Outside NYC, 1986-2009 (Box 7)
  - Exhibits: "The Fifth Province", 2010 (Box 7)
  - Exiles and Evangelizers: Catholic Ireland's Western American Empire, 2010 (Box 30, Folder 9)
- F
  - Fairfield University: Irish Studies, 2000 (Box 7)
  - Family History Research Aids, 1991-2009 (Box 7)
  - The Family Tree International Newsletter, 1994-1997 (Box 7)
  - Famine: Canada - Grosse Íle, 1992-2009 (Box 7)
  - Famine/Genocide Remembrances (U.S.), 1994-2009 (Box 7)
  - Famine Symphony Concert World Premiere, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Farrell, Patric, circa 1915, 2008 (Box 21)
  - Feast of Saint Patrick, 2009 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Feile - Festa Literary Arts Journal, 2009 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Festivals: New York City and New York State [1 legal-size folder, 1 oversize folder], 1869, 1986, undated (Box 7)
  - Festivals: United States (outside NYC and Washington D.C.) [1 legal-size folder, 1 oversize folder], 1973 (Box 7)
  - Festivals: Washington D.C., 1996 (Box 7)
  - The Fifth Province County Societies in Irish America, 2013 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Fiftieth Anniversary Easter Week Commemoration Associated Irish Societies of New York, 1966 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Fighting for Freedom: From Belfast to Boston, undated (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Film Events: NYC, 1988 (Box 7)
  - Film Events: Outside NYC, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Film Fleadh Foundation, 1998 (Box 7)
  - Film: On Irish and Irish America, 1940-1996 (Box 7)
  - Film: On Irish and Irish America, circa 1997 (Box 7)
  - Film: On Northern Ireland, 1990-1997, undated (Box 7)
  - Film Reviews, 1992 (Box 7)
  - The Film Society of Lincoln Center/Glucksman Ireland House, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Fitt, Jerry, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Fitzpatrick Manhattan Hotel, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - Fitzpatrick, Thomas, undated (Box 7)
  - Flannery, Michael, 1983, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Flannery, Michael: Long Kesh Hunger Strike Commemoration, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Florida Irish Festivals, undated (Box 21)
  - Flynn, Raymond L. (Mayor of Boston, Ambassord to the Vatican), undated (Box 8)
  - Foley, Thomas (Speaker, U.S. House of Representatives), 1989 (Box 8)
  - Food and Beverage Importers, 1992-1999 (Box 8)
  - Fordham University: Institute of Irish Studies, 1978-1979, 1998-2002 (Box 8)
  - Four Courts Press Dublin, 1997-2001 (Box 8)
  - Fourth Annual Feis: Irish-American Club Washington, D.C., 1979 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Frances Pope Memorial Foundation, 1984-1989 (Box 8)
  - Frances Schervier Home and Hospital, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Freedom Struggle, undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - The Friendly Sons of the Shillelagh, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - Friends of Fianna Fáil, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Friends of Irish Freedom, 1994-2017 (Box 8, Box 34, Folder 23, Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Friends of Loughinisland, 1994 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Friends of Sinn Fein, 2007, 2012 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - From Galway to Broadway and Back Again, 2010 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - From New York to Corrymore: Robert Henri & Ireland (Georgia O'Keeffe Museum), 2011-2012 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Fundraiser for Richard Johnson, Irish Political Prisoner in U.S., undated (Box 31, Folder 6)
- G
  - G.A.A. Diary of a Century: A Chronicle of Events in Mayo & Elsewhere, 1885-1984 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Gaelic Athletic Ass. of New York, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Gaelic League Notes, undated (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Gaelic Park, 2001 (Box 8)
  - The Gaelic Society (NYC), 1969 (Box 8)
  - Gaffney, Nan Fitzpatrick, 1997 (Box 8)
  - Gallagher, Father Michael J., 1996 (Box 8)
  - The Gallagher Initiative, undated (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Gallagher, Miriam, 1992 (Box 8)
  - Gallon, Dale, undated (Box 8)
  - Galway Association of New York, Galway Supporters Club of New York, Club Galway (IRL) Banquet Cruise, 2010 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Galway Bay (Mary Pat Kelly), 2011 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - The Galway Men's S&B Association of New York Memorial Mass, undated (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - The Galway Men's S&B Ass'n, Inc. St. Patrick's Dinner-Dance, 1986 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Galway Show, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Garden State Annual Irish Festival, 1992 (Box 8)
  - The Gathering - Ireland, 2013 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Gay, Dorothy Kelly (Mayor of Somerville, MA), 2001 (Box 8)
  - Genealogy [1 legal-size folder, 1 oversize folder], undated (Box 8)
  - Gift and Novelty Sellers (UK and Ireland), 1999-2001 (Box 8)
  - Gift and Novelty Sellers (U.S.) (4 folders), 1994-1996 (Box 8)
  - Gleason, Thomas, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Global Exchange Reality Tours, 1998 (Box 8)
  - Glucksman Ireland House, 1991-2018 (Box 9, Box 22, Box 35, Folder 1-3, Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Glucksman Ireland House New York University, 2004; TW_AIA_013_ER_2
  - Glucksman Ireland House NYU 20th Anniversary Gala, 2013 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Golden, Senator Marty, 2012 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Good Morning! First, the Bad News... with Cathal MacCoille of Morning Ireland, 2013 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - The Good Shepherd: Silver Jubilee Dedication Book, 1937 (Box 9)
  - Graduate Irish Studies Conference, 1993-1994, 1999 (Box 9)
  - Gralton, Jimmy, 1945 (Box 21)
  - The Great Hunger Memorial/Irish Hunger Memorial, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Great Hunger Museum Quinnipiac University, 2010-2016 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - The Great Irish Fair, 1981-1998 (Box 9)
  - The Great Irish Famine Teacher's Synopsis, 1996 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Greeley, Father Andrew, 1971-1976 (Box 9)
  - The Green Apple (An Tull Glas) - A Sense of Ireland in New York, 2009 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Green Linnet Irish Music Party, 1993-1996 (Box 9)
  - Green Linnet Records, 1993-1998 (Box 9)
  - Greenwood Cemetery -- Map of Irish Gravesites, undated (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Greeting Cards, circa 1993 (Box 9)
  - The Grian Association, 1999-2004 (Box 9)
  - GRIAN Conference on Irish Studies, 2002-2003 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Grimes Travel, 1991-1997 (Box 9)
  - Guests of the Nation, 2011 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - A Guide to Irish Studies in the U.S., 1982, 1987, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Guinan, Matthew, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Guiness Fleadh, 1997 (Box 9)
  - Guiness Import Co., 2001 (Box 9)
  - Guinness Oyster Festival, 1997-1999 (Box 9)
- H
  - Haas, Richard, 2001 (Box 9)
  - Haggerty, James, 1992 (Box 9)
  - Hammond, John Lawrence, 1921 (Box 21)
  - The Harp and Shamrock Club, Inc., 1956 (Box 9)
  - Harrison, George, 2000 (Box 9)
  - Haughey, Charles J., 2000 (Box 9)
  - Heaney, Seamus, 2013 (Box 38)
  - The Hedgemaster (Irish Cultural Society), 2012, 2021-2025 (Box 31, Folder 22, Box Shared Tamiment 209, Folder 10)
  - Hibernian Benevolent Association of the City of Troy, 1841 (Box 21)
  - Hidden Ireland: A First Celebration of Ireland in Documentary Film, 1922-2010 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Hoboken's 23rd Annual St. Patrick's Day Parade, 2010 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Hofstra University Irish Studies Program, 2008 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - How the Orangemen Began, undated (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Hughes, John D.D., 1866, undated (Box 9)
  - Hume, John (Northern Ireland Map), 2005 (Box 9)
  - Hunter Celtic Club, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Hynes, Charles "Joe", undated (Box 31, Folder 26)
- I
  - Images and Representations of Irish Americans, 1989 (Box 9)
  - Imagine Ireland: A Year of Irish Arts in America 2011, undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Immersion Weekends, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Immigrants in U.S. ("New Irish"), circa 1980-1989 (Box 9)
  - Immigration History Newsletter, 1984-2000 (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Immigration to North America, 1985-2006 (Box 9)
  - Immigration: Notes and Bills, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Immigration Reform, circa 2005 (Box 9)
  - Independent Irish Society Inc., 1985 (Box 9)
  - The Independent Shavian- Journal of the Bernard Shaw Society, 2010-2011 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Information Ireland, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Inside Ireland, 2003 (Box 9)
  - Institute for Irish-American Studies (Lehman College), 2010-2013 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - International Conference on Hunger, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - International Gaelic Hall of Fame, 1972-1974 (Box 9)
  - International Peoples' Tribunal on Human Rights and the Enviroment, 1997 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - International Rebel Music Festival, 1986 (Box 9)
  - International Socialism 51, 1972 (Box 21)
  - "Internment: The Need for Proper Safeguards" (Dr. Claire Palley), undated (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Invitations, 1995, 2000 (Box 9)
  - Iona College Libraries: Bibliography of Gaelic Language Materials, 1998 (Box 9)
  - The IRA on Film and Television (Mark Connelly), undated (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Ireland, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Ireland America - The Ties that Bind, 2011 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Ireland Before the Republic Politics and Culture, 1922-1949 Lecture, 2003-2004 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Ireland and the British Empire Lecture, 2004-2005 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Ireland Chamber of Commerce USA, 1988-1994 (Box 9)
  - Ireland Day - New York Stock Exchange, 2011 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Ireland Digest, undated (Box 9)
  - Ireland Diskovered, 1997 (Box 9)
  - The Ireland Fund, undated (Box 9)
  - Ireland's Great Hunger (An Gorta Mor: The Quinnipiac University Collection), 2010 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Ireland's Great Hunger Institute (Quinnipiac University), 2014 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Ireland's Great Hunger Museum, 2012 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Ireland International Institute, 1992 (Box 9)
  - Ireland on Parade, 1964 (Box 9)
  - Ireland Today - Bulletin of the Department of Foreign Affairs, 1977, 1982 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Ireland of the Welcomes, 1966, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Ireland United Nations Security Council, 2021-2022 (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - Ireland's Children (NY), 1975-1979 (Box 9)
  - Irish Academic Press, 1997-2000 (Box 10)
  - Irish Ad Hoc Society in Support of Jesse Jackson, circa 1988 (Box 10)
  - Irish Advocate Magazine, 1992 (Box 10)
  - Irish America Magazine, 1992 (Box 10)
  - Irish American Athletic Club, 1908-1915, 2010 (Box 10)
  - Irish-American Athletic Club Annual Dinner, 1911 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Irish American Bar Association of New York, 2012 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Irish American Book Company [2 folders], 1999 (Box 10)
  - Irish American Building Society [4 folders], 1996-2003 (Box 10, Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Irish American Center, 1982 (Box 10)
  - Irish American Committee to Elect David Dinkins, 1989 (Box 10)
  - Irish American Cultural Center of NY, 1985-1992 (Box 10)
  - Irish-American Cultural Festival, 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Irish American Cultural Institute, 1972-2017 (Box 10, Box 35, Folder 7, Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Irish American Cultural Organizations, 1981 (Box 10)
  - Irish American Fenian Society, Inc., 1986, 1992 (Box 10)
  - Irish American Film Foundation, circa 1998-1999 (Box 10)
  - Irish American Hall of Fame, undated (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Irish American Heritage Center, 1994 (Box 10)
  - Irish American Heritage and Culture, 2005 (Box 54, Folder 16)
  - Irish American Heritage and Culture, 2010 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Irish American Heritage and Culture Committee, 1996-2015 (Box 35, Folder 8, Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Irish American Heritage and Cultural Committee Department of Education, 2010 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Irish-American Heritage and Culture Week Committee, Inc. [2 folders], 1985-1995 (Box 10)
  - Irish-American Heritage Month Events, 1991-1995, 2000 (Box 11)
  - Irish American Heritage Museum, 1988-2012 (Box 11, Box Shared Tamiment 029, Folder 5, Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Irish American Heritage Week, 1982 (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - The Irish American Hour, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Irish American Labor Coalition, 1986, 1994 (Box 11)
  - The Irish-American Link, Mar 1976 (Box 21)
  - Irish American Movement: The Irish Race Convention, 1994 (Box 11)
  - Irish American Network Foundation, 1991 (Box 11)
  - Irish American Parade Committee, Inc., undated (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - Irish American Parade Committee, Inc. - 36th Annual Installation Dance St. Patrick's Auditorium, 2011 (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - Irish American Partnership, 1993 (Box 11)
  - Irish-American Political Action Association, 1975 (Box 11)
  - Irish American Press, undated (Box 11)
  - Irish American Public Action Committee, Inc., 1992-1996 (Box 11)
  - Irish American Singles Association, undated (Box 11)
  - Irish American Singles Club of N.J., undated (Box 11)
  - Irish American Social Club of Washington, D.C., 1969, 1971, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - Irish American Society of Greater Richmond, undated (Box 11)
  - Irish-American Society of Nassau, Suffolk and Queens, Inc., 1961-2006 (Box 11, Box 21, Box 54, Folder 17)
  - Irish-American Society of Nassau, Suffolk, and Queens Inc. (59th Installation of Officers Dinner Dance), 1989 (Box 32, Folder 27)
  - Irish-American Society of Nassau, Suffolk, and Queens Inc. (61st Annual St. Patrick's Day Parade), 2011 (Box 32, Folder 28)
  - Irish-American Society of Nassau, Suffolk, and Queens Inc. (The Harvest Moon Ball), 1996 (Box 32, Folder 29)
  - Irish American Teamsters, 1994 (Box 11)
  - Irish American Unity Conference, 1998-2013 (Box 11, Box 35, Folder 9)
  - The Irish Ancestral Research Association, 1990-1991 (Box 11)
  - Irish Apostolate in Brooklyn and Queens, 1993 (Box 11)
  - Irish Arts Center, 2009-2013 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Irish Arts Center (An Claidheamh Soluis, Inc.), 1971-2013 (Box 11, Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Irish Arts Center: Traditional Dance Festival, 1990-1993 (Box 11)
  - Irish Arts Center: Traditional Music Festival, 1988-1996 (Box 11, Box 38)
  - Irish Arts Festival, 1999-2000 (Box 11)
  - Irish Arts Forum of Rockland County, 1994 (Box 11)
  - Irish Arts Foundation, 1996, 2003 (Box 11, Box 33, Folder 2)
  - The Irish Association of Nova Scotia, 1995 (Box 11)
  - Irish Book Center, 1976-1977 (Box 11)
  - Irish Books and Graphics, 1992-2008 (Box 11, Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Irish Books and Media, Inc. [2 folders], 1980-1981, 1991-2005, undated (Box 11)
  - The Irish Bookshop, 1994-2000, undated (Box 11)
  - Irish Brigade Association, 1991 (Box 11)
  - Irish Brigade Gift Shop, 2002 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Irish Bronx Theatre Company, 1993-1995 (Box 11)
  - Irish Business Organization of New York [2 folders], 1991-1999 (Box 11)
  - Irish Business Organization Trip to Ireland's Great Hunger Museum at Quinnipiac College, 2013 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Irish Center Leeds, 1995 (Box 12)
  - Irish Civil War, 2010 (Box 22)
  - Irish Club, 1939 (Box 54, Folder 18)
  - Irish Communist Organization Pamphlet #7: The Fenians by Karl Marx, 1977 (Box 21)
  - Irish Connections(Premier Issue), 2000 (Box 12)
  - Irish Craft and Gift Exhibitors, circa 1998-2001 (Box 12)
  - Irish Crime Fiction: A Festival, undated (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Irish Cultural Society, 1996-2017 (Box 12, Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Irish Cultural Society Foundation (Maryland), 1995 (Box 12)
  - Irish Cultural Society of Garden City, 1991, 2012-2019 (Box 12, Box 22, Box 38)
  - Irish Cultural and Sports Centre, Inc., 1990-1995 (Box 12)
  - Irish Culture Week Committee, 1980 (Box 12)
  - The Irish Diaspora Project, 1993-1994 (Box 12)
  - The Irish Directory, 1996 (Box 12)
  - The Irish Echo, 1978-1979, 1994-2000 (Box 12)
  - Irish Echo Political Cartoons, 1991; TW_AIA_013_ER_1
  - Irish Edition, circa 1997 (Box 12)
  - The Irish Emigrant, 1994 (Box 12)
  - The Irish Emigrant Vote Campaign, 1991-1992 (Box 12)
  - Irish and English dictionaries, 1995 (Box 12)
  - Irish Eyes (Arizona), 1995 (Box 12)
  - Irish Family History Events, 1999- (Box 12)
  - Irish Family History Forum, Inc., 1993-1995 (Box 12, Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Irish Famine Curriculum Committee, circa 1995 (Box 12)
  - Irish Famine/Genocide Committee, 1996- (Box 12)
  - Irish Fest (Milwaukee), 1991-1997 (Box 12)
  - Irish Festival of the Arts (NYC), undated (Box 12)
  - Irish Festival of Stars, 1960, 1965 (Box 12)
  - Irish Film Association (NYC), 1991-2014 (Box 12, Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Irish Film New York, undated (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Irish films, 2002-2017 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Irish Focus (non-profit group), circa 1993 (Box 12)
  - Irish Food Distributors, Inc., 1996-1999 (Box 12)
  - Irish Franciscan Brothers, 1968-1986 (Box 4, Box 12)
  - Irish Gazette, 2008 (Box 12)
  - Irish Genealogical Foundation, 1990 (Box 12)
  - Irish Genealogical Society, 1991-1994 (Box 12)
  - Irish Georgian Society, 1966-2017 (Box 12, Box 35, Folder 17)
  - The Irish Georgian Society and Chantal O'Sullivan, 2011 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - The Irish Georgian Society Gala Dinner, 2011 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - The Irish Georgian Society St. Patrick's Day Celebration, undated (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - The Irish Globe: News for Irish Immigrants, 1995 (Box 21)
  - Irish Guide Dogs Association, 1995 (Box 12)
  - The Irish Herald, 1998 (Box 12)
  - Irish Heritage & Culture, 2005, 2013 (Box 33, Folder 9-10)
  - Irish Heritage Breakfast, Scott Stringer, 2020 (Box 54, Folder 19)
  - Irish Heritage Day, 2012 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Irish Heritage Society of America, undated (Box 12)
  - Irish Heritage and Spirit Celebrated in 252nd New York City St. Patrick's Day Parade, 2013 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Irish History Calendar, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - The Irish Hour (Chicago and San Francisco, 1961 (Box 12)
  - The Irish Hour, 1953 (Box 12)
  - Irish Hunger Memorial, 1995-2004 (Box 12)
  - Irish Illustrated (Vol 1, no. 9), 1956 (Box 12)
  - Irish Immigrant Society Pamphlet - A Lecture on the Mixture of Civil and Ecclesiastical Power, in the Government of the Middle Ages, 1843 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Irish Immigration Center, 2001 (Box 12)
  - Irish Immigration Reform Movement, 1989-1991, 2007 (Box 12, Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Irish Immigration Reform Movement (NYU Glucksman Ireland House Exhibition Materials), 1987-2007
    - Paper Materials (Box 43, Folder 19, Box 44, Folder 1-2)
    - Digital Materials, TW_AIA_013_ER_4
  - Irish Labor History Society, Dublin, undated (Box 12)
  - Irish Language Courses, 1998-2001 (Box 12)
  - Irish Language Events, 1983-1997 (Box 12)
  - Irish Language Schools, 1975-1998 (Box 12)
  - Irish Lesbian and Gay Organization, 1993-2000 (Box 12)
  - Irish Literature, 1971-1979 (Box 12)
  - Irish Media Image Group, 1983-1986 (Box 12)
  - Irish Music Flyers, 1976, 1995-1996, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Irish Music Record Albums, TW_AIA_013_ER_3
  - The Irish Music, Song, and Dance Workshop and Lecture Series, 2006 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Irish National Caucus, 1983-2015 (Box 12, Box 35, Folder 19, Box 33, Folder 16)
  - The Irish in Newark and New Jersey: Exhibition at the Newark Public Library, 2007 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - The Irish in New York, 2013 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Irish Night at Shea Stadium, 1997, 2000 (Box 12)
  - Irish Northern Aid, undated (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Irish Northern Aid Testimonial [2 folders], 1987, 1994 (Box 12)
  - Irish Northern Aid and The Irish People: research paper and supporting documentation, 1972-2006 (Box 12)
  - Irish Northern Aid Hunger Strike Defense Fund Flyer, circa 1981 (Box 54, Folder 20)
  - Irish Organizations (various), circa 1960-1969 (Box 13)
  - Irish Pavillion (letterhead), undated (Box 22)
  - Irish Pages: A Journal of Contemporary Writing, 2008 (Box 13)
  - The Irish People Newspaper Bumper Sticker, undated (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Irish Progressive League (photocopies of originals), 1918, undated (Box 13)
  - The Irish Radio Singers, 1958 (Box 13)
  - The Irish Railroad Workers Museum - A Shrine, undated (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - Irish Rebel Music, 1987-1988 (Box 13)
  - The Irish Rebel Theatre, circa 1980 (Box 21)
  - The Irish Repertory Theatre [5 folders], 1989-2009 (Box 21, Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Irish Republican Army (IRA), undated (Box 9)
  - Irish Republican Clubs, USA and Canada, 1972-1973 (Box 13)
  - Irish Republican Movement, 1961 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Irish Roots Magazine, 1992 (Box 13)
  - Irish Socialist Federation in America, undated (Box 13)
  - Irish Studies at Boston College, 1998 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - Irish Studies: Course Lists/Syllabi, 1988-1996 (Box 13)
  - Irish Studies Events, Conferences and Lectures, 1994 (Box 13)
  - Irish Studies Programs in Ireland [4 folders], 1970-2006 (Box 13)
  - Irish Studies Programs in the United States, 1987-2002 (Box 13)
  - Irish Studies Program - University of Missouri-St. Louis, 2005-2006 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - The Irish Summer (L'Ete Irlandais), 1997 (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - Irish Task Force of the National Lawyer's Guild, 1986 (Box 13)
  - Irish Teachers' Association [2 folders], 1974-1983 (Box 13)
  - The Irish Times (On the Web), 1994 (Box 13)
  - Irish Tourist Board in America [2 folders], 1978-1998 (Box 13)
  - Irish Trade Board in America, 1994 (Box 13)
  - The Irish Transport and General Workers' Union, 1934 (Box 21)
  - Irish Travel Agents Association Inc., 1976-1992 (Box 13)
  - Irish Travel Agents Association of New York, 1979 (Box 13)
  - Irish Vise, 1995-1997, undated (Box 13)
  - The Irish Voice, circa 1990-1999 (Box 13)
  - The Irish Way (Irish American Cultural Institute), 1992 (Box 13)
  - Irish Weekends, 1991-1998 (Box 13)
  - Irish Workers Club of Boston, circa 1930-1939 (Box 13)
  - The Irish World, 1920 (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - Irish World: Centennial celebration, 1971 (Box 21)
  - Island: Arts from Ireland, 2000 (Box 13)
  - Ivers, Eileen, 1996 (Box 13)
- J
  - James Haggerty of Tir Conaill, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 27)
  - James Joyce Quarterly, undated (Box 13)
  - James Joyce Society, 2020 (Box 54, Folder 21)
  - James X, undated (Box 33, Folder 28)
  - Jean Butler - hurry, undated (Box 33, Folder 29)
  - The Jeanie Johnston Project, circa 1990-1999 (Box 13)
  - Jerry McCabe Fellowship Program, 1997-1998 (Box 13)
  - Jersey Shore Irish Festival, 1997 (Box 13)